CIVIL ENGINEER IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

SEBASTIAN RAMIREZ RAMOS



CONTACT INFORMATION

\subseteq	seba.ramirez.ramos@gmail.com
\cap	999521264

$\stackrel{\frown}{\Box}$	Nov	15,	1995

linkedin.com/in/sebastian-ramirez-ra
mos/

SKILLS

- Python Advanced
- Django Advanced
- MySql Intermediate
- PostgreSQL Intermediate
- Html/CSS Intermediate
- Teamwork
- Problem Resolution
- Optimization

LANGUAGES

- Inglés | Advanced.Efset.org/cert/VZNZpm
- Spanish | Native

OBJECTIVE

Professional with +2 years of experience in Backend development with Django Framework and outstanding skills in project management, Python and Java programming, and database management (PostgreSQL, MySQL). I am a hard worker, persistent and focused, capable of leading teams and managing stressful situations to achieve goals in the established time. My main objective is to continue growing professionally, add value to each project and continue learning and improving my skills.

EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPER

Conectapi. Santiago, Chile | Aug 2021 - Dec 2021

Complete development of a marketplace type web solution, defining the architecture, models (ER design) and tech to be used. The Python and Django framework was used, with which the Backend was developed and for the Frontend html with css, with MySQL as a database, and GitHub was used for version control.

BACKEND DEVELOPER

TeNecesito. Santiago, Chile | Dec 2021 - Jun 2023

Backend development of an existing application, REST API type, using the Python and Django framework, which was used for the creation of endpoints with raw information return and also for the creation of functions with the data, to obtain statistics. We worked with PostgreSQL for database management. Some relevant tasks were: integration with other APIs with the system using Python, database management and creation of new functionalities. GitHub was used for version control of the code. For team management, something similar to the Scrum methodology was used.

EDUCATION

DEGREE IN ENGINEERING SCIENCES

Pontificia Universidad Católica de Valparaíso. Valparaíso, Chile | Mar 2014 - Mar 2019

CIVIL ENGINEER IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Pontificia Universidad Católica de Valparaíso. Valparaíso, Chile | Mar 2014 - Dec 2020